Where do you go when the record is over...
Saturday Night Fever is a music, drama film directed by John Badham.
Tony spends his Saturdays at a disco where his stylish
moves raise his popularity among the patrons.
But his life outside the disco is not easy and things
change when he gets attracted to Stephanie.
Tony Manero, played by John Travolta.
Stephanie, played by Karen Lynn Gorney.
Bobby C., played by Barry Miller.
Joey, played by Joseph Cali.
Double J., played by Paul Pape.
Annette, played by Donna Pescow.
Saturday Night Fever is a 1977 American dance drama film directed
by John Badham and produced by Robert Stigwood.
It stars John Travolta as Tony Manero, a young Italian-American man who spends his weekends dancing and drinking at a local
disco while dealing with social tensions and disillusionment in his working class ethnic neighborhood in Brooklyn.
The story is based on "Tribal Rites of the New Saturday Night", a mostly
fictional 1976 New York article by music writer Nik Cohn.
A major critical and commercial success, Saturday Night Fever had a
tremendous impact on the popular culture of the late 1970s.
It helped popularize disco around the world and initiated a series of
collaborations between film studios and record labels.
It made Travolta, already well known from his role in the popular
TV sitcom Welcome Back, Kotter, a household name.
He was nominated for the Academy Award for Best Actor for his performance, at
the time becoming the fourth-youngest nominee in the category.
The film showcases aspects of the music, dancing, and subculture surrounding the disco era, including
symphony-orchestrated melodies, haute couture styles of clothing, pre-AIDS sexual promiscuity and graceful choreography.
The Saturday Night Fever soundtrack, featuring songs by the Bee Gees,
is one of the best-selling soundtrack albums worldwide.
Travolta reprised his role of Tony Manero in Staying Alive in 1983, which was
panned by critics despite being successful at the box office.
In 2010, Saturday Night Fever was deemed "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant" by the
Library of Congress and selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry.
Adjusted for inflation, it is one of the
highest-grossing R-rated films released in the U.S.
in the 1970s, with a total box office gross of $673,899,098 in 2024.
The film explores themes of dancing master, dance
performance, female lover, disco, lyrical.
The tone is emotional.